(监狱装甲押运列车)
我们已经抓住了逃犯
我们现在要把犯人带回去
(丹萨里监狱)
Lucky ring on.
幸运戒指戴上了
I feel so much safer.
我感觉安全多了
Grip it. We're coming in hot!
抓紧了,准备开战
Hold on!
抓紧了
Clear!
安全
Let's go.
跟我走
What's the holdup?
磨蹭什么呢
Nothing, we're on our way. Let's go!
没事,马上就完,快走啊
Your dude's trippin'!
这哥们儿在梦游吗
Doc!
医生
Hey, forget this maniac!
别管这疯子了
I'm not leavin' him!
我不会扔下他
Doc!
医生
Move!
快上来
Whoa. You just gonna roll up on me, huh? After eight damn years.
你是来看我的吗,都过了八年了
What's up with that?
你这是干嘛
You were in a black-ops prison that doesn't officially exist.
你被关在了一个外界不知道的秘密监狱里
I just got the location from a guy named Church,
我从一个叫教堂的人那儿打听到了方位
an agency spook.
这个人是个密探
Excuse me?
你说什么
Agency official. Relax.
他是政府部门的人
I think you're in a time warp, man.
现在才来救我
What a waste of life. You make one damn mistake!
浪费我多少生命,我就犯了一次错误
Wasn't a mistake. it was stupid.
那不是犯错,那是犯二
If you'd have done that to me, I would've chopped you into pieces.
如果你再敢那样对我,我就把你大卸八块
You would've tried.
有本事你试试
Hey, you wanna thank the guys?
嗨,谢谢兄弟们吧
The guys? Where are our guys? Hammer? Woodsman?
兄弟们,我们的兄弟呢,铁锤呢,樵夫呢
Gone.
都不在了
Dead gone?
彻底不在了
Yeah.
对
Damn.
见鬼
Heard you killed more people than the plague.
听说你杀的人不计其数
How 'bout that?
很牛吧
Why do they call you Doctor Death?
所以大家叫你死神医生
Used to be a medic.
我是当过医生
But that was a long time ago.
不过很久以前的事了
So Why'd you get locked away?
怎么会被关起来的
Tax evasion.
因为逃税
So you all that's left of the Expendables?
敢死队就剩下你们几个人了
We're it.
是啊
We started out with five. Built up to 22.
敢死队最早是五个人,后来发展到二十二人
I see Barney's still hanging the tags up there.
我看到巴尼还把身份牌挂在那儿
Said that jinglin' sound the tags make,
据说这些牌子会发出叮当声
that's a reminder that
就像在提醒我们
our brothers are still here.
那些兄弟还活着
Somewhere.
活在某个地方
So come on, Viking.
行了,维京人
Give an old-schooler your blade.
把刀交给大叔吧
Or else you might find your tags up there jinglin', too.
不然你的牌子也会挂在上面
Jing-a-ling. Jing-a-ling, jing-a-ling.
叮当叮当响,叮当叮当,叮当叮当
Sharpen it when you're done.
用完了磨快点儿
I think your friend's a little off.
你的朋友神叨叨的
Come on, Christmas. He's been in a hole for eight years.
很正常,他在那个洞里关了整整八年
How'd he get so lucky?
他怎么进去的
He tried pulling off this half-assed political assassination for a few bucks
他为了一点儿小钱,在非洲东部的一个地方
in this place called Swaziland. And he blew it.
搞了一次计划不周密的政治暗杀,结果失败了
Self-destructive.
原来是自己作死
Yeah, something like that.
差不多,就这样,不过
But you know what he is? He's a good medic.
他是一个好医生
Well, I don't need a checkup.
我又没得病
Why are you so sarcastic?
你怎么说话老带刺儿
You're vague.
你掏浆糊
- Vague?   - Secrets, idiot.
- 掏浆糊,老是绕来绕去  - 得了
I mean, why do you take me halfway around the planet to save this
你为什么不远万里带我来这儿
medical genius, as you describe him?
救这么一个,你所谓的医学天才
For what?
为了什么
He's an Expendable.
他是敢死队的
Oh, my God. Come on.
天呐,唬谁呢
He's an Expendable.
他是敢死队的
So, he's one of the flock?
你说的是真的
Let me tell you something.
我跟你说吧
If you were incarcerated for years,
如果你在牢里关了好几年
I'd come and save you.
我一定会来救你的
Thanks, hero.
谢谢了,英雄
But I doubt it.
我才不信呢
And I know you'd do the same for me.
我知道你也会来救我的
- Truthfully?   - You'd let me rot?
- 想听真话  - 宁愿让我死在牢里
Exactly.
绝对的
Hey, Doc.
嗨,医生
What's your name?
你叫什么
Christmas.
叫圣诞
Is that real?
是你真名
Authentic.
千真万确
Is that real, too?
这也是真的
Oh, no, I spend three hours every morning
哦,不是,这个,是我每天早上花3个小时
putting this on with a black Biro.
用黑色圆珠笔画上去的
This is real. Authentic.
我这个,是真的,千真万确
Original. Look at that.
原创的,瞧瞧
Balance is a little off.
哦,平衡感有点退步
You a knife man?
你会使刀
Best. Ever.
绝对是,最棒的
I'm the Knife Before Christmas.
名气比圣诞节还要响
Ain't that right, Barney?
对吗,巴尼
If you say so.
你说是就是
Probably free-stylin' with a blade while you were still suckin' on your daddy's titty,
我玩刀的时候,你大概还是,刚断奶的小屁孩儿
tryin' to learn how to eat with a spoon.
在学习怎么用勺子吃饭
Yeah. Is that another little secret you was keeping there, Mr. Vague-o?
是啊,这是你保守的另一个秘密吧,浆糊先生
Just stay out of my brain, would you?
别老猜我在想什么
I tell ya. I can't wait to get home.
我可是急着要回家了
Eat some good food, put on some fine threads,
吃点儿好的东西,穿上好的衣服
break out my '49 Pontiac,
坐进我那辆庞蒂亚克
kick that baby until the engine blows up!
使劲踩油门,直到发动机飞起来
You didn't tell him, did you?
你没告诉他,是吗
Tell me what?
告诉我什么
We're not going home.
我们不回家
We're stoppin' a dealer named Victor Minns delivering a shipment of thermobaric bombs.
有个叫维克多·明斯的商人在运送温压炸弹
我们要去阻止他
Oh, come on, man!
噢,开什么玩笑
That shit is hellfire.
那玩意儿是地狱之火
Hey, routine stuff.
这是个常规任务
You know, why didn't you just pick me up on your way back?
你干嘛不等完成任务之后再来接我
We're a man short.
我们正好缺人
Well, you know I'd love to party with you boys,
我很愿意跟你们一起玩儿
but, uh, I don't have my shit.
不过,我现在没有趁手的家伙
- That's my shit.   - it is your shit.
- 这是我的家伙  - 是你的家伙
Doc, did you thank the guys for helping you out?
医生,他们救你出来,你谢他们了吗
Say somethin'.
说出来
Uh, listen up.
听好了
It's been a long time since I had a reason to say thank you.
我已经很久没有找到,说谢谢的理由了
So I just wanna...
所以我只想
I, you know...
你们知道
He's getting his rhythm.
越说越利索了
l wanna say, uh...
我想说
Thank you.
谢谢
His sincerity's overwhelming.
态度相当诚恳呐
Think I'm gonna weep.
我都要哭了
You know what? Enough.
嗨,伙计,够了
Can you not be sarcastic?
别老跟刺儿头似的
That was great, Doc. Seriously.
你说得很好,医生
- That was good.   - Pretty good.
- 很好  - 相当的好
You haven't talked for a long time.
毕竟你已经很长时间没有说过话了
- You got the gift.   - So you heard?
- 你很有天赋  - 你听了
It's like riding a bike.
就像骑车
To me it was like Churchill's best moment.
超过丘吉尔的鼎盛时期
- Gettysburg Address.   - I think I made my point...
- 堪比葛底斯堡演说  - 我想我可能打动了
Yeah, it moved me. it moved him.
对,打动了我
- I moved you, too?   - Stunning delivery.
- 我也打动了你  - 震撼人心的演讲
Stunning.
震撼人心
- Doc.   - Yeah?
- 医生  - 嗯
Great to have you back.
很高兴你回来
No better place to be. Yeah.
反正也没别的地儿可去
(索马利亚 摩加迪苏)
'Bout time you boys showed up.
跟你们说了,让你们慢点
- Nice boat.   - Thanks, ladies. Stole it myself.
- 船不错  - 谢谢,女士们,我亲自偷的
Got three more just like it patrolling the harbor.
还有三艘这样的,在港口巡逻
Two-man ground teams every 400 meters.
地面每隔400米有两人巡逻
Good work.
干得好
Just 'cause you can fly a plane don't make you smarter than me.
会开飞机不能代表你比我聪明
Sure it does.
谁说不能
So you the reason I've been stuck down here in this shithole?
就因为你,他们把我丢在这破地方
Shithole? Brother, you have no idea.
破地方,你知道什么叫破吗
What the hell is that?
那是什么玩意儿
This bitch'll solve all your problems.
这宝贝儿能解决你所有的问题
Yeah, maybe for 10 seconds before it blows its wad.
是啊,能硬起10秒钟,然后就不行了
So now you got that problem, too?
这么说你也不行喽
You walked into that one.
这是你自找的
Come on, look alive, look alive.
行了,出发了,出发了
Good luck.
祝大家好运
It was all under control.
都在我控制之中
Yeah, that's what it looked like.
是啊,看上去是这样
He saw you, he didn't see me.
他看见你了,他没有看见我
Where ya been?
去哪儿了
Had a doctor's appointment.
瞧医生去了
Catch up with you boys later.
我不陪你们了
Where's he goin'?
他要去哪儿
Happy New Year, motherfuckers!
新年快乐,你奶奶的
Makin' a housecall.
小心上面
Doc, go.
医生,上
Oh, Sally, the man attacked me with a knife.
噢,小子,居然跟我玩刀
- Damn. He's good.   - Maybe to you.
- 他挺厉害  - 得了吧
- You're gonna wanna see this.   - See what?
- 你们该看看这个  - 看什么
I'll show you.
稍等一下
Damn. He's really good.
嚯,他真厉害
- Say it again, I'll shoot you.   - Chill.
- 再说一次,我就崩了你  - 安静
Get in.
进吧
Where's the bomb?
炸弹在哪儿
It'll be here.
可能在那儿
Barney, it looks like the target is right on time.
巴尼,目标来得很准时
There's Minns. Let's take him out fast.
找到明斯,我们尽快解决他
Barney, I gotta put you down.
我要把你们放下去了
- It can't be.   - What can't be?
- 不可能  - 什么不可能
We gonna shoot these guys or what?
到底杀还是不杀
What's the holdup?
怎么不行动
He's dead.
他早死了
Who's dead?
谁死了
Stonebanks.
斯通班克斯
Stonebanks!
Come on, get in, get in, get in, get in, get in!
快点儿,进去,进去,进去
Barney, move! Go, go, go!
巴尼,快进来,快,快,快
Ah! Come on!
快,行动
It's time to mow the lawn!
该修草坪了
Told you. Ten seconds.
我说吧,就10秒钟
Hang on! I found you a ride!
坚持住,给你们找了辆车
Time to go!
该撤了
Come on!
快点儿
Go, go, go!
走,走,走
- How much we gettin' paid for this?   - Not enough.
- 这趟活儿能赚多少  - 多少都不够
Go right!
往右
- You're not gonna fit!   - Always negative.
- 我们过不去  - 你老这么悲观
I'm getting carsick.
我都要吐了
Hang on, Doc!
坚持住,医生
- Right side!   - Got it!
- 右面  - 收到
Get out!
快走
Come on!
快点儿
Caesar, we're coming your way! Where are you?
凯撒,我们来找你了,你在哪儿
In this filthy river. Behind you!
在你后面,那条脏河里
Try to stay as close as you can!
你尽量靠我们近点儿
Make room for Caesar!
给凯撒让个座
Move your asses!
快点儿让开
What was that?
什么玩意儿
A huge black guy in a boat.
一条船加个黑大个
Hold it, hold it! You got it goin'!
全速前进,继续开
- You all right?   - Yep.
- 没事儿吧  - 没事儿
Pull over.
停车
Ahhh! Incoming!
炸弹来了
Move! Move!
快走,快走
(教区纪念医院)
Maybe this will bring you luck.
希望这戒指能帮你挺过去
Is he gonna make it?
他能挺过来吗
I don't know.
不知道
Who did this?
是谁干的
Stonebanks.
斯通班克斯
I thought you killed him.
他不是被你杀了吗
So did I.
我也这么想
He shot Caesar to get back at me.
他打凯撒是为了报复我
You know, I'm getting out of this business.
我准备洗手不干了
And so should you.
你也该退了
Not yet.
现在还不行
If you need any help with Stonebanks...
如果要人帮你对付斯通班克斯
I'm supposed to meet a guy named Church.
我要见的是个叫教堂的人
I know you were.
我知道
So who are you?
那你是谁
Operations Officer Drummer.
我是行动指挥官,鼓手
You don't have to worry about Church anymore.
你不用再担心教堂了
He's, um... He's out of the picture.
他,跟我们没关系
Jesus, Ross. What a mess.
天呐,罗斯,真是一团糟
We gave you everything.
我们什么都给你了
Target, opportunity,
目标,机会
all the intel you could ask for,
还有你需要的所有情报
and you got decimated
可是你,却打了败仗
and my target walked away.
让目标逃之夭夭
Am l wrong here? Am I missing something?
我说错了吗,有什么不对
Yeah. Church said the target's name was Victor Minns.
有,教堂说目标的名字叫维克多·明斯
- And?   - He was wrong.
- 怎么了  - 他弄错了
His real name is Conrad Stonebanks.
那个人的真名叫康拉德·斯通班克斯
We knew him only as Victor Minns.
我们只知道他叫维克多·明斯
Arms dealer, made billions selling to every psycho warlord
军火贩子,亿万富豪
in Africa and the Middle East.
靠倒卖武器给非洲和中东发家起家
Has his own mercenary army.
他有自己的雇佣军部队
He's personally responsible
就是他,严刑拷打
for torturing and killing
并且杀死了
two of the best men
我认识的,两个最优秀的人
I ever knew. Friends.
还都是我的朋友
I don't give a shit what his name is.
我不在乎他到底叫什么
I don't like him.
我讨厌他
I want him as bad as you do.
我跟你一样想抓住他
This happened on my watch.
这事就发生在我的眼皮底下
You fucked up,
你,把它搞砸了
and I'm wearing it.
我,还得给你扛着
I'll find him. Again.
我会想法再找到他
You got one more shot.
你还有一次机会
Nice to finally meet you, Barney.
很高兴见到你,巴尼
Your men are shot to shit.
你的人伤得不轻
What are you gonna do for a team?
你要怎么组建团队
Don't worry about it. I'll handle it, Drummer.
这你不用操心,我会搞定
Relax.
放松点儿
You're gonna give yourself a stroke.
老这么紧张容易中风
What's with these guys?
这都什么人呐
You mind?
让一下
(俄罗斯 莫斯科)
Do you think when the artist painted this
当画家画这幅画的时候
he ever thought it would go for such a ridiculous price?
压根没想到它能卖到这个天价
I mean, what is it? It's just some paint,
不过是些颜料,画笔
brushes, some cheap canvas. What's the big deal?
便宜的画布,这有什么呀
It's shit. What do you want for it?
狗屁不是,你开价多少
- Three million.   - Done.
- 三百万  - 成交
Done.
成交
You know, it's very hard for me to say this,
要知道,要知道,我真的很不愿跟你说这些
but at one time, you guys were the best.
你们曾经是最棒的
Maybe still are.
也许现在还是
But nothing lasts forever.
可是不会永远这样
Hard as it is to hear,
虽然很难接受
we aren't the future anymore.
未来已经不属于我们了
Unfortunately for us,
很遗憾我们老了
we're part of the past.
我们只属于过去
You, uh... You going somewhere with this?
你,到底想说什么
As I see it, if we keep this life up,
在我看来,再这样下去
the only way this thing ends, for all of us,
我们这些人只会有,一个结局
is in a hole in the ground and no one giving a shit.
被埋进土里,连个来扫墓的人都没有
Now, if that's the way I'm supposed to go out, I can live with that.
既然这是我自己选的路,我能接受这个结局
For me.
我可以
But what I can't live with,
但我不能接受
and won't live with,
也不会接受
is taking you with me.
让你们跟着我这样
What're you saying? That's our call.
说什么呢,我们是自愿的
I'm changing things now.
我要改变一下了
You. Me.
你,我
All of us.
我们大家
It's over.
结束了
- We're done.   - Done?
- 散伙了  - 散伙
You break me out to cut me loose?
你救我出来,然后甩了我
You'll survive.
你会适应的
You all will.
你们都会
Live your lives while you can.
抓紧时间享受生活吧
Where're you goin', Barney?
你要去哪儿,巴尼
You think you just pull the plug and that's it?
你以为说结束就能结束了
Just did.
没错
Yeah? Well, it doesn't work that way!
是吗,哪有你想的那么简单
- What?   - We've been through the mud,
- 干嘛  - 我们一起风风雨雨
the shit, and the blood.
流血流汗
And I've saved your ass more times than I can count.
我都数不清救过你多少次了
You owe me a shot at this son of a bitch that took Caesar down.
我们要干掉那混蛋
We're not doing that.
我们不会这么做
When I joined, I joined for the whole ride.
我入伙的时候,买的可是全程票
I know you did.
我知道
Ride's over.
旅程结束了
(内华达州 拉斯维加斯)
Bonaparte.
波拿巴
Sorry to hear about Caesar. Hope he pulls through.
凯撒的事我很遗憾
He's a good one. The good ones are rare.
但愿他能挺过来,他这种好手可不多
Yeah.
是啊
Well, here we are again. What do you need?
又见面了,要我做什么
A new team. Retired the old ones.
组个新队,老队员都遣散了
Welcome to the 21 st century.
欢迎来到21世纪
What kind of guys you looking for?
要找什么样的人
Young, hungry, willing to take a bullet.
年轻,有雄心,不怕吃枪子儿
I'm going after Stonebanks.
目标是斯通班克斯
Stonebanks.
斯通班克斯
Glad to see I'm not the only one slipping a notch.
跟不上形势的人不止我一个
Stonebanks is dead, my friend. Mortuus diu.
斯通班克斯早翘辫子了
No, he's not.
不,他没死
That's not good.
这可不妙
If he's half of what he used to be,
就算他能力减半
four or five ain't gonna cut it. You're gonna need 50.
也得五十个人才能对付得了他
Gotta move fast. No time.
时间紧迫,你得快点儿
If I gotta do it fast
这么着急
I can't guarantee the best.
我可没法保证质量
Just give me some that don't give a damn.
给我几个不怕死的就行
What, it's a one-way ticket?
怎么,这回是单程票
Could be.
有可能
Fine. I've got a line on a few head cases.
好吧,我认识几个不要命的疯子
A couple of these guys you'll probably end up shooting yourself.
疯到你自己都想宰了他们
Wait. What about these guys?
等等,这些家伙怎么了?
They anything?
到底怎么了
These guys are pussies.
都是软脚蟹
(怀俄明州 大提顿山)
Goes by Thorn. Expert hacker. Drone pilot.
我们去见索恩,专业黑客,无人机驾驶员
Did 18 months for hacking into Seattle's Central Operating System.
他花了18个月黑进了西雅图的中央操作系统
Shut down the whole city for three days.
让整个城市停转了三天
Why the hell would he do that?
他干嘛要这么干
'Cause he can.
就为了证明自己
What?
怎么
I'm not looking for an office worker.
我不需要坐办公室的人
Oh, that's not him.
那不是他
That's him.
那个才是
Another one with a death wish. You two got a lot in common.
他也是个不要命的,你们有很多共同点
I could do that.
这我也行
You know what? I'm gonna come right out and say it.
知道吗,我会跳过来说
I belong on you.
我们很配
One, two...
一、二
- You can't do that.   - No.
- 这你可不行  - 没错
I want a special rate on that one.
给个优惠价吧
Yeah, yeah, hazard pay.
是啊,是啊,这个有风险
Always on the damn road going someplace you don't give a damn about.
我好像总是在去,一个我根本就不愿意去的地方
Beats standing still.
总比待着不动好
Yeah, I've got two ex-wives and three kids who've lost my number would disagree.
我那两个再也不跟我联系的前妻和三个孩子,可不这么想
Hey, did you turn off the auto-pilot?
你关闭自动驾驶了
I didn't touch the auto-pilot.
我没碰过那个按钮
Give me the booze.
把酒给我
Are we off course?
偏离航线了
Where the hell are we? Here, hang on a second.
我们这是在哪儿啊,稍等一下
Is that...
那个是
Is that the Big Dipper? Yeah, we gotta turn around.
是北斗星吗,我们得掉头了
Next candidate is an expert at field craft and close-quarters combat.
下个候选人是伪装及近身搏击高手
- Luna.   - Hi.
- 卢娜  - 嗨
Ambitious young lady. Meet a friend of mine,
野丫头,这是我朋友,巴尼·罗斯
Barney Ross. Barney Ross, Luna. Luna, Barney Ross.
卢娜,卢娜,这是巴尼·罗斯
- Hey, how're you doin'?   - Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Ross.
- 嗨,你好  - 幸会了,先生
Gentlemen, follow me. I have your table waiting.
先生们,跟我来,已经安排好了
Come on. Live a little.
来吧,享受一下生活
So, Luna, how are things?
卢娜,最近怎么样
You know. Gets old.
老一套
What you wanna do? You wanna go, bro?
你干嘛,想打架吗
If you guys will excuse me.
我失陪一会儿
All right, so what are we doing here?
我们来这儿干嘛
Have a drink.
喝一杯
Where's the candidate?
候选人在哪儿
Right there in the red dress, about to chop those guys in half.
穿红裙子的,正要把那些家伙打趴下
The hostess?
那个女招待
Not the hostess. She's the bouncer.
她不是招待,她是保安
I could do that.
这我也能行
You wanna slip on a dress and give it a shot?
要不你穿上裙子试试
Men.
臭男人
She's good.
她很棒
You ought to see her without heels.
你该看看她不穿高跟鞋的样子
(亚利桑那州 阿帕契 交叉口)
When was your last checkup?
你上次体检是什么时候？
I don't know. A while back.
有一阵子了,记不清
High cholesterol, plaque, all that stuff?
说你高血脂,动脉硬化
- Yeah, pretty much.   - Yeah.
- 对,差不多  - 嗯
Except with me they found a lump on my lung.
我不是,他们说我的肺里有个肿块
Very dark, they said.
还说颜色很深
Oh, no.
哦,不
I sure didn't see that comin'.
我可真没想到
Well, what are you going to do?
那打算怎么办
Try to make as much money as I can, fast as I can.
在最短的时间里尽可能多赚点钱
Yeah.
是啊
For those kids, you know. The ones I don't talk to.
留给那几个孩子,虽说都不联系
Make some kind of good impression on 'em
我想死后
when I'm gone.
给他们留点儿好印象
Sad, isn't it?
很可悲,是吧
Yeah, it is sad. I'm sorry.
是啊,很可悲,很遗憾
- Ah, it's all bullshit. I'm fine.   - What?
- 我瞎扯呢,我没病  - 什么
Just checking you're still human.
看你还有没有人性
Had you going there, though, didn't I?
你被我绕进去了吧
- Yeah, you did, God damn it.   - All right. Good.
- 是啊,我都相信了,该死的  - 不错啊,好
That can never happen again.
不许再忽悠我
- I'll never trust you again.   - All right.
- 否则我不相信你了  - 好的
Next kid's a bit of a dark horse.
接下来这孩子是匹黑马
Just came across my desk.
他的资料刚送来不久
I don't like throwing in wild cards,
我不喜欢发什么外卡
but this guy's creds were too good to pass up.
可他条件太优秀,错过可惜
Anybody seen Felipe?
谁看到费利佩了吗
Yo, Felipe!
嗨,费利佩
Looks good, Bonaparte.
他的身手真不错
Yeah, not bad.
是啊,还行
You finally got it right.
你总算会挑人了
Damn.
行啊
Felipe Silva, meet Barney Ross.
费利佩·席尔瓦,见见巴尼·罗斯
Galgo. You sent me another fake resume?
高格,你是不是又发了一份假的简历给我
Eh, Mr. Ross, I can do what you need,
罗斯先生,你要我做什么都行
whatever you need.
做什么都行
I am healthier than I look, stronger than I look,
我比看上去要健康
faster than I look.
比看上去要强壮
Actually, faster than anybody I know.
速度要更快
Shit. You were born in 1984?
见鬼,你难道是84年出生的
Of course not!
我当然不是
But I feel like I was born in '84.
可我感觉自己就像是84年生的
Do not waste your time. Barney, we're leaving.
你别浪费时间了,巴尼,我们走
Mr. Ross.
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross, Mr. Ross! Please.
罗斯先生,罗斯先生,求你了
You see,
听我说
it's like I have discovered the Fountain of Youth.
我就像是,就像是找到了青春泉
I mean, not the Fountain of Youth.
我是说,不是那个青春泉
Ponce de Leon discovered that one.
而是那个庞塞·德·莱昂找到的
By the way, another great Spaniard, like myself.
顺带说一句,他可是,和我一样,都是西班牙人
No. No. Mr. Ross,
不,先生,罗斯先生
age is just a state of mind.
年龄,只是一种心态
You know, you're only old when you surrender,
只有当你投降,当你放弃时,才会真的变老
when you give up.
而我现在
And I haven't. Not yet.
还没有投降
- Galgo, this shit has got to stop.   - I got to go.
- 高格,别再这样  - 我得走了
This is the third time this month.
求你了,这是这个月第三次了
Seriously, move on!
说真的,去干点别的吧
What's this guy's story?
这家伙什么情况
Actually, I feel a little sorry for him. His last team dropped him.
老实说,我挺同情他,原来的团队不要他了
Back in the day, you couldn't catch him. Very fast.
放在过去,没人追得上他
- Maybe even faster than you.   - No way.
- 他非常快,也许比你还快  - 不可能
Oh, maybe. But what am I gonna say? It's a young man's game.
哦,有可能,可我能怎么说呢,这是年轻人的游戏
I need a job!
我需要工作
All I know what to do is killing people!
我唯一会干的事就是杀人
And I do that very well! God damn it!
而且我干得非常好
(加州 爱德华空军基地)
What's the story on this guy?
这家伙有什么经历?
- Found him at DARPA.   - DARPA?
- 我在达帕找到的  - 达帕
Yeah, it sounds like a town in North Africa.
对,听上去像个北非的城镇
Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency,
其实是国防高级研究计划局
where they send the brightest military minds to develop next-gen weapons.
他们召集了最聪明的军事天才开发新式武器
Google it.
你用得着他
I'm not looking for a weapons nerd.
我可不需要书呆子
Then you've come to the right place.
那你算来对地方了
Yo, Marlito!
嗨,马尔斯
Mars, I'd like you to meet Barney Ross.
马尔斯,这是巴尼·罗斯
As shooters go, Mars is as gifted as they get.
枪炮到了马尔斯手上,就像遇到了知音
Whatever you say.
你说的好
What do you say?
你怎么说
What I've got here is an XM25 assault rifle. Laser ranged.
这是把XM25突击步枪
25mm high explosive airburst rounds.
激光测距,25毫米烈性空爆弹
Can be programmed to detonate over or behind a target.
能编程让它在目标前面或者后面爆炸
He'll do.
我要了
Final candidate, John Smilee.
最后一位候选人,约翰·斯麦利
Guy's got the most heat in the industry.
这家伙有这条街上最多的团队
A lot of skills, Marines, Special Operator. But there is an issue.
掌握各种技能,当过海军陆战队特种兵,就是,有一个缺点
What issue?
什么缺点
A classic authority problem.
嗯,老一套,目无领导
There's a couple more swimming around in there, too.
这里面的好苗子还挺多啊
Sorry, Barney, for wasting your time like this.
抱歉,巴尼,浪费你的时间了
He's not the guy I thought he was.
是我看错了
No.
不
I wanna meet him.
我想见见他
John. Meet Barney Ross.
约翰,来见见巴尼·罗斯
Didn't do much to impress out there today, did you?
你今天的表现好像不够抢眼啊
You called me, I didn't call you.
是你自己来找我的
Took a dive for the money?
为了钱故意放水
Maybe you like getting your ass kicked in front of strangers?
还是你喜欢被人打得满地找牙
What do you guys want from me?
你们找我干嘛
You runnin' from somethin'?
你是在逃避吗
I don't know you.
我不认识你
But I know you.
可我认识你
- Oh, yeah?   - Yeah.
- 是吗  - 是啊
How's that?
怎么说
Maybe he thinks you've got potential.
他觉得你有潜质,而我们又在赶时间
We're short on time. That about right?
是这意思吗,就这意思
That's about it.
那是你的问题
Well, that's your problem.
你的问题是
And your problem is you're rolling around in the dirt
为了那点可怜巴巴的小钱儿
for chump change.
就满地打滚
I hear you lost a few friends in the desert.
我听说你在沙漠失去了一些朋友
They bought it. You didn't. You wear the guilt.
他们死了,你没死,你感到很愧疚
I've been there. He's been there.
我跟你一样,他也是
We all lived it.
我们接受现实了
But you don't know me.
你不了解我
I know the type.
我了解你这类型
Bonaparte, you were right.
波拿巴,你说得对
You did waste my time.
我是在浪费时间
You didn't waste your time.
你没有浪费时间
If you're going after Stonebanks, we might wanna talk about financials now.
既然你的目标是斯通班克斯,那我们就得谈谈酬金了
Normally, it's just 10%,
一般只要先付10%,可考虑到
but I figure with Stonebanks in the equation,
你的对手是斯通班克斯
I might wanna get my fee, well, possibly now.
我现在就得拿到,全部的费用
Right.
好的
I mean, not that you're not good for it.
我不是说你不行
Just, if you don't mind.
只是,希望你别介意
I don't mind.
我不介意
Sounds like you don't have too much faith in me.
你好像对我没什么信心
I don't.
的确
How was your vacation?
假度得怎么样
Ready to go to work?
准备工作了吗
Did you find him yet?
你找到他了
He's in Bucharest putting together a deal with some Albanian mobster.
他在布加勒斯特,跟一帮阿尔巴尼亚人谈交易
You've got 36 hours. That's your window.
你有36个小时,这是你唯一的机会
After that, he's back off the grid.
之后,他会消失得无影无踪
Satellite map. Coordinates for where he'll be.
这是卫星地图,上面有他位置的坐标
Interesting guy, your friend Stonebanks.
你的这位朋友,是个很有意思的家伙
You're not gonna like this,
你可能不情愿,不过
but they want him alive.
上面要求抓活的
Are you kidding me?
你是在耍我吗
They wanna try him at The Hague
他们想在海牙国际法庭
for war crimes.
因战争罪起诉他
You're gonna give this guy a chance in court?
你居然想给他上法庭的机会
It's not my decision.
又不是我要这样
No. Never is.
是啊,从来都不是
- That's the way it's gotta be.   - Right.
- 上面定了,只能照办  - 是啊
The Agency's got a local safe house. You're gonna need it.
我们的机构在当地有个安全屋,你会用得着
Don't trash the place.
别搞得太乱
- Heard you got a job.   - That's right.
- 听说你有任务了  - 是的
Who the hell are they?
那些家伙是谁
They're with me.
我的人
But we're not?
我们不是
Gunner, I told you everything I had to tell you back at the bar.
宫纳,该说的我在酒吧里都跟你说过了
Stop drinking so much.
别喝那么多酒
You wanna get yourself killed. With those youngsters?
带着那帮毛头小子
Do us all a favor and get the hell outta here.
你是想找死啊,为了大家好,赶快走吧
Wheels up in 10.
10点钟出发
Come on.
瞧瞧去,走吧
If your guys wanted to fight, why didn't they just get married?
你那些兄弟想吵架,还不如找人结婚呢
You're seriously smoking next to aviation fuel?
你是真心要在航空燃油边上抽烟
Amateur.
真业余
Amateur assholes.
是个业余混蛋
Who are you calling asshole, Grandpa?
你叫谁混蛋呢,老爹
Grandpa's about to crush your windpipe.
老爹是要把你的气管捏碎
What's this? Your toy?
这是什么,你的玩具
Boy?
小朋友
- You wanna dance, big guy?   - Hey!
- 想跳舞,傻大个儿  - 嗨
It's just a job.
我们是来干活的
Come on, let's go.
行了,我们走
Bunch of has-beens still trying to be hard.
过气的老东西还装什么强悍
You're young and you're dumb.
你个年轻的脑残
Jing-a-ling, jing-a-ling.
叮叮当,叮叮当
Keep it. You're gonna need it.
留着吧,用的上
Never thought you would call in that favor.
没想到你会请我来帮忙
Don't look so happy about it.
别太得意忘形
Do you mind?
介意吗
This is the least of your worries.
你少操那份心
Look, here's an idea, how about we focus on the assignment?
不如来讨论下任务吧?
Now, does anyone know anything about this Stonebanks?
有谁知道这个通班克斯?
Stonebanks was SASR.
通班克斯曾是SASR
- Australian Special Forces.   - And that's all you know?
- 澳大利亚特种空勤团  - 就这些?
- Well, it's more than you two know.   - Really?
- 已经比你俩知道的多了  - 真的?
So, you're both useless.
你们两个废材
Here's another idea...
要我说啊...
Why don't you assholes take it outside?
你们还不如直接脱裤子亮腚放屁?
You got a minute?
想聊聊吗
What do you need?
什么事
Tell me more about this guy we're going after.
跟我说说要抓的那个人
Doesn't matter. You were hired to do a job.
没必要,你是来干活的
How 'bout answering why we're doing this job?
那能不能告诉我,为什么要干这活儿
I owe you a salary. That's it.
因为我要付你工资
Why are we going after Stonebanks?
为什么要抓斯通班克斯
You have a hard time taking orders, don't you?
要你听我的命令很费劲吗
If I don't know what they are, yeah.
你的命令不明确
I know you don't give a damn about us. I get that.
我知道你不把我们,放在眼里
But just tell me why you wanna take out this guy so bad.
可你得告诉我,为什么这么想抓那个人
Thirty seconds to drop!
离跳伞还有30秒
Copy that.
收到
Let's go.
我们走
I can take care of myself.
我自己能行
Twenty seconds to drop.
还有20秒
Ten seconds!
还有10秒
(罗马尼亚 布加勒斯特)
We're on.
行动吧
This guy's got more muscle than a cartel king.
这家伙的保镖比世界首富还多
Maybe he's overcompensating for something.
大概是要弥补什么
What are you drinking down there, Barney?
你在下面干嘛呢
Is that a vanilla latte or something?
在喝香草拿铁
Stay sharp.
保持警惕
Luna? Move.
卢娜,上
Think again, mister, because I won't.
因为我不会再忍下去了
I promise this won't happen again.
如果再发生这种情况的话
- Move the car.   - I'm talking to you!
- 车过来  - 我跟你说话呢
Nice driving, Mars.
你怎么回事
Good performance.
车技真棒
Yeah, too good. Any closer and I'd beat his ass.
演技不错,是啊,好过头了,再近一点儿,我揍扁他
I believe her.
这我相信
We got him.
搞定了
Man, this guy's protected better than the President.
天呐,这家伙保护得比总统还好
Yeah, and his crib's like a five-star fortress.
是啊,他的老窝跟五星级堡垒似的
That's why we're not taking him there.
所以不能在那儿动手
And the hotel is full of guests.
酒店里又都是客人
- So where do we hit him?   - At the meet.
- 那怎么办  - 会面的时候
We hit him from all four sides. Hit him hard.
我们从四面发动进攻,狠狠地打
Okay. Um, so, our plan is to, what?
好的,那么,我们的计划是
Kick down the door and start spraying bullets?
把门踹开,然后开枪一顿狂扫
It's a great plan if it was 1985.
要在85年,这是个好计划
And what is that supposed to mean?
你这话是什么意思
You heard me.
不明白吗
- You got a better plan?   - Much better.
- 你有更好主意吗  - 多的是
Let's hear it.
说来听听
Thorn, you're up.
索恩,你说吧
Okay. I'm the plan. Um...
好吧,有个主意
This ought to be good.
但愿是好主意
First, I hack the security grid main server.
先黑进安保系统的主服务器,嘣
Boom. Bypass the motion-detector lasers and biometric sensors.
绕开运动探测器的激光和生物监察
Pow. Override the surveillance video and CCTV systems.
啪,然后重写监控视频和闭路电视监控系统
Ba-bam. And we are in.
叭嘣,我们进去了
It's child's play.
斯麦利想出来的
- Just like that?   - Just like that.
- 就这么简单  - 就这么简单
Just like that.
就这么简单
Exactly like that.
就是这么,简单
You better be right.
但愿行得通
Let's go!
行动吧
So, Why'd you let your team go?
干嘛解散原来的团队
If you stick around long enough, you're gonna buy it. it was time.
你在这行待久了就会理解,应该解散
They didn't seem too happy about it.
他们好像不情愿呐
If you're looking to go the family route,
如果你也想把团队当成家庭
it's the wrong job for you.
那这工作不适合你
There are different kinds of family.
家庭有各种各样的形式
And when my life is on the line,
当我身处险境的时候
it's my family fighting with me.
家人会和我并肩作战
You know what I mean.
你懂我的意思吗
Yeah, I know what you mean.
是的,我懂你意思
(布加勒斯特现代艺术馆)
Right on time.
时间正好
Ladies first.
女士优先
Go ahead then, Thorn.
那你先走啊,索恩
Will you shut up and get in the sewer?
闭嘴,快下去吧
Okay.
行了
(启动)
And, ladies and gentlemen, we officially have eyes in the sky.
女士们先生们,现在我们在空中有眼线了
Copy that. Let's do this.
收到了,开始吧
Thought you'd never ask.
可算开始了
Good to go.
可以了
Good luck, boys.
祝你们好运
Whoa. Shit.
噢,见鬼
What's the problem?
怎么了
The buyer. They're early.
是买家,早到了
Threat just doubled.
危险加倍
You're early.
你来早了
What do you think?
觉得怎么样
Eh, it's okay.
还不错
When Cain slew his brother,
该隐杀了自己的兄弟
God banished him
上帝把他逐出了
from civilization.
文明世界
But before that, he placed a mark on him.
在那之前,他给该隐做了个记号
Not as a felon's brand,
这记号不是为了说明他是罪人
but to protect him from roving hunters.
而是为了保护他不被猎人杀死
Customs does not X-ray artwork.
海关不会用X光检查艺术品
It ruins the oils.
会破坏颜料
Very good.
非常好
There you have it.
归你了
- Pleasure.   - As always.
- 谢谢  - 不必客气
Can you access nuclear weapons?
你能搞到,核武器吗
I might.
也许
But, generally, I find people are a little too emotional for ownership.
不过,我发现人在这个东西的,所有权问题上容易冲动
And I'd hate you killing all my other customers by accident.
我可不希望你有意无意地,把我其他客户
Or on purpose.
都弄死了
In position.
我已就位
就位
Set.
I pay you what you want.
你想要多少钱都行
Let me think about it.
我考虑一下
We're on.
注意,斯通班克斯在移动
Stonebanks is moving, watch it.
我喜欢小耗子
Try again.
再试一次
Open sesame.
芝麻开门
Go, go, go!
走,走,走,快走
(接受重写 重载安全门锁)
Luna? Go.
卢娜,上
Barney Ross says hello.
巴尼向你问好
Nice job.
干得漂亮
Trench, you copy?
战壕,收到吗
I'm waiting.
我等着呢
Package secured.
货搞定了
Hurry up. It's boring.
动作快一点,等得无聊死了
Why don't you just put a bullet in his head and be done with it?
你干嘛不给他一枪,一了百了
Hey! Hey! Hey! You said we were taking him in.
嗨,你说过我们要带他走
Oh! Good mornin'.
早上好
Are these your students?
这些是你的学生
Hey, kids. What'd you learn tonight, huh?
孩子们,今天学到了什么
Yeah, what happened to the old crew?
那帮老家伙们去哪儿了
Oh, that's right.
噢,我想起来了
They stuck their noses into other people's worlds
那帮老家伙去管别人的闲事
And got fatally injured.
结果死的死伤的伤
Now they're the Deletables.
现在他们成了已死队了
Hey! You hear that, kids?
嗨,记住我说的话
Take note, 'cause that's what you're doing right now.
你们也在走这条路
Can we shut his mouth?
能让他闭嘴吗
You're talking pretty tough to a guy who's incapacitated, which is good for you.
对一个丧失行动能力的人说话这么凶,真了不起
Is it?
是吗
Why don't you cut me loose? I'll open your meat shirt and show you your own heart.
不如给我松绑,我把你的心挖出来给你看看
Hey, Barn.
我说巴尼
Why don't the two of us just end this?
我们两个做个了断吧
What do you say? Mix it up...
你说呢,狠狠干一仗
Either you snapping my spine or me snapping yours.
要么你折断我的脊椎,要么你折断我的
You know? Make it snappy.
怎么样,来个痛快的
He thinks I'm joking. I'm not joking.
你当我开玩笑,我可没有
You should see me when I'm angry.
你该看看我发飙的样子
You'd be very impressed. Then very dead.
你绝对会印象深刻,然后就死了
So, come on, pal. Anything you wanna get off your chest?
来吧,老兄,想说什么就说吧
Come on, lay it out. I'm a good listener.
快点儿,说出来,我洗耳恭听
You gonna take me back to the Has-Been Crew?
你是想把我带回到那些老队员面前
Carve me up around a fire? Very tribal.
围着篝火把我撕碎,就像原始部落
When we stop,
等我到了
I'm gonna break every bone in your body.
我会把你身上所有的骨头都打断
And drop what's left at The Hague.
把剩下的交给海牙
The Hague.
海牙国际法庭
I finally made the big time.
我这回终于搞大了
I'm a war criminal.
我是战犯了
Keep laughin'.
你就笑吧
Do you think that you can just deliver me like a package?
你以为,你能把我当个货物,运过去吗
We were close once.
我们以前多亲密
See, we started this whole Expendables thing together.
最早是我们一起组建的敢死队
See? Look, I've got the marks.
瞧,我这儿还有记号呢
A bit faded, but we had a falling out.
好像有点儿褪色了,后来我们闹翻了
You went dark.
你走上黑道了
It's a dark business, Barney.
这就是个黑暗的营生
Don't pretend you're not in it.
别装得好像你没干过
The baddest survive. Those are the rules. I didn't make 'em up.
最坏的人才能活下来,这我可没瞎说
You see, Barney here was content to work for the small-end money, as an employee.
巴尼为了一丁点儿小钱,就愿意给人家打工卖命
Now, being boss is more lucrative.
当老板要赚的钱多得多
But that's a concept that somehow eluded you.
不过这事你不会懂的
Plus, you've got that pesky moral conscience.
另外你还有讨厌的良心
God, that stuff gets in the way. He thinks he's the good guy.
这玩意儿最碍事了,他老把自己当好人
- Keep talkin' while you can.   - Sure.
- 趁你还能说话就说吧  - 好啊
You got a conscience, and that makes you weak.
有良心你就会变得软弱
Success, real success
成功,真正的成功
is being willing to do the things that other people are not.
是愿意去做别人都不愿意做的事情
Not everyone's as sick as you.
不是所有人都跟你一样恶心
Oh, but you are.
哦,不过你是
Did you kill anyone today, Barn? Blow any shit up?
今天你杀人了吗,炸了什么地方吗
How 'bout you, kids? Kill anyone?
孩子们,你们杀人了吗
Before you all start grabbing bricks to stone me at The Hague,
在海牙国际法庭审判我之前
you might wanna check your own hands for blood.
你们也许该看看自己身上有没有沾着血
But I digress. Where was I?
噢,我跑题了
Yes. Business is booming, right?
对了,生意很红火
A chopper here, a missile there. Guns, whatever.
这儿卖架直升机,那儿卖颗导弹,还有那些枪
When suddenly, a competitor, if you can call Uncle Sam a competitor,
然后,突然一个竞争对手,我把山姆大叔叫做竞争对手
hires my own team, Barney and the whole gang to whack me.
雇了我自己的团队
Things got ugly real fast and a lot of people got dead.
巴尼和所有队里的人来对付我
然后事情急转直下,好多人都死了
Three former brothers-in-arms.
三个亲如兄弟的战友
You shut your mouth.
闭上你臭嘴
Three Expendables, our brothers.
三个敢死队员
Men we ate with, fought with, bled with.
都是好兄弟,我们一起吃饭
Dead. He puts three slugs into my chest.
一起战斗,一起流血,都死了
Thank God for body armor. Even I thought I was dead.
他朝我胸口开了三枪,多亏我穿了防弹衣
And then he boogies out with the casualties.
当时我都以为自己死了,可他跟个没事儿人一样
All dead because you couldn't stay out of my business!
兄弟们都死了,就因为你非要干涉我的生意
Shut your mouth!
给我闭嘴
Go on, do it!
来呀,动手啊
- Go on!   - It's what he wants.
- 开枪啊  - 你想干嘛
Oh, it's hard to fathom. I can't believe you forgot.
真是没想到,不敢相信你居然忘了
What?
什么
That it's hard to beat an enemy when he's living inside your own head.
你很难把一个,你一直放在心里的人当成敌人
See, you tie me up like an animal,
你把我像牲口一样的绑起来
lead me to the slaughter. You humiliate me, disgrace me.
送到屠夫面前,你羞辱我,贬低我
Now, when the time comes to kill you,
如果以后我有机会,一定会杀了你
And it will, I will not use a weapon, I will use my hands.
我不会用武器,我会用手
Because I want you to feel the way that I feel right now.
因为我要让你体会我现在的感受
Jesus, we were brothers.
我们曾经是兄弟
What's that?
那是什么
It's a GPS tracker! It's a GPS tracker!
GPS追踪器,他有GPS追踪器
How 'bout that?
怎么样啊
Hold it!
等等
We may need 'em. I need a body. Find him.
他们还有用,把巴尼的尸体找来
What happened?
怎么回事
We found a shitstorm.
阴沟里翻船
It's gonna get worse.
还会更糟糕
This came in for you 10 minutes ago.
10分钟之前发给你的
Hey, Barney!
嗨,巴尼
My search party's dead, so I'm taking it you're still with us.
我的搜索队都死光了,所以我想你应该还活着
Now, you should've killed me when you had the chance
你当时真该杀了我
'cause that's your last window. It's gone.
那是你唯一的机会,现在没了
Now, I got something to show you here.
好了,我有点儿东西给你看
We got Harpo, Groucho,
我们有哈珀,格鲁乔
Gummo and Chica! Yeah, yeah, yeah.
伽莫,还有琦科尔,耶
Hey, give her a little squeeze there, Krug.
克鲁格,抱抱她
She's so pretty.
这可是个大美女啊
Personally, I'd chalk it up to collateral damage.
对我来说,弄死几个无辜的倒霉蛋不算什么
I don't give a fuck. But I know you.
不过,我了解你
Forty-eight hours and they're gone for good.
48小时之后,他们就真完了
If you want 'em, come get 'em.
想救他们,你就来吧
What are you gonna do?
你要怎么办
Looking a little strung-out there, kids.
噢,绳子勒得挺紧的吧
And this is what you get for being pawns in Barney's moral chess game.
这就是你们在巴尼的道德棋局里当小兵的结果
That one looks a little slack.
那个看上去有点儿松
You know, I feel most bad for you.
我最替你感到惋惜
I don't give a shit how you feel.
我才不管你怎么想呢
I do. I have a daughter. I have feelings.
真的,我有个女儿
Anyway, you know, when the CIA...
我也有感情,无所谓了
I presume that's who you're working for.
当中情局,我假设你们为中情局干活儿
The CIA. Am I right?
中情局,我猜得对吗
I bet you don't even know who you're working for.
你们不会连自己为谁干都不知道吧
What, for Barney? Do you know who he's working for?
为巴尼吗,你们知道他为谁干吗
Does he know who he's working... It gets very confusing.
他知道自己为谁干吗,越扯越乱了
Anyway, when the CIA wanted guys
反正当中情局要找人去危险的地方
doing the dangerous work in the dangerous places, they called us.
干那些危险的活儿,会找我们
When they didn't wanna get their hands dirty, they called us.
当他们不想脏了自己的手,会找我们
Yep. We cleared every hotspot they had.
对,我们帮他们清理所有让他们头疼的地方
We bumped the bad guys so that the good guys could roll in lookin' like heroes.
我们把坏蛋赶跑,让这些好人能过来装英雄
We killed a lot.
我们杀了很多人
But we saved more lives than you can possibly imagine.
但我们拯救的生命多得超乎你们的想象
Then, the boys on the Hill, wanting no loose ends,
然后,那些家伙们就想过河拆桥杀人灭口
tried to bury me.
他们想做掉我
I was an American
我以前是美国人
working for America.
为美国这国家卖命
Was.
以前是
They'd eat their own children.
他们连自己的孩子都吃
The lesson here is
教训就是
never do business with the government.
千万不要跟政府做生意
But I'm gonna save you that heartache. You never will.
还是别抱幻想了,他不会来的
So you're getting your old team?
你要召回老队员
No, I burned that bridge.
不,我不会找他们的
You know, your pride is gonna get you killed.
你的自尊心会害死你
Better me than them.
我死总比他们死好
- So, you're really gonna go back?   - Yeah.
- 你真的要回去救人  - 当然
- Alone?   - Yeah.
- 一个人去  - 没错
You're an idiot.
你这个笨蛋
Thanks for showing up.
谢谢你帮忙
I guess our favors are done.
我这忙已经帮完了
But you're still an idiot!
你真是个笨蛋
How the hell did you find me?
你怎么找到我的
People talk. I hear things.
这个嘛,没有不透风的墙,我又比较会打听
You got a mission. I can help.
你有个任务,我能帮忙
My name is Galgo.
我的名字叫,高格
Let me fill you in. l am good.
我跟你介绍一下,我很棒
Very good. At warfare.
打起仗来,非常棒
You know, good memory. Afraid of nothing.
记忆力超强,什么也不怕
I want to be your friend.
我想成为你的朋友
I don't need a friend.
我不需要朋友
Yes, you do. Everybody does.
你需要,谁都需要朋友
You know, I don't have any friends. That's why I know.
听着,我一个朋友也没有,我知道朋友有多重要
But besides my friendship issues, what I really need now is something to do.
不过除了交朋友之外,我现在最需要的是找点事情做
Well, not just anything, but what I was born to do.
不是随便找点事情做,而是要做我最擅长的
Best bet, this is a one-way trip.
那太糟了,这是单程车
Excuse me, sir,
抱歉,长官
but one-way trip is better than no way.
坐单程车,总比没车坐好
Which is the way I live now.
我现在是什么车都没得坐
Help me with the crate.
帮我搬箱子
Sir.
长官
On the plane, Gogo.
搬飞机上,格格
On the plane. Yes, sir.
搬飞机上,是
Gogo? No, I'm not Gogo. No, Galgo.
你叫我格格,不,我不叫格格
- Galgo. Gogo sounds like a Parisian hooker.   - Galgo.
- 我叫高格,格格像巴黎妓女的名字  - 高格
"I am the bridegroom of death."
我,是死神的新郎
Those are the lyrics of a Spanish Legion old song
这是西班牙军团一首老歌的歌词
that we used to sing when we were on a mission in Croatia.
我在克罗地亚执行任务的时候经常唱
You know, that's where I met Mingo.
我就是那里认识的明格
Yeah. The best point man ever.
对,他是有史以来最棒的侦察兵
Some kind of savant, you know.
他就像是这方面的专家
No ambush this guy couldn't sniff.
没有他发现不了的埋伏
And under fire, the coolest cat ever.
遭到攻击的时候他最镇定
Just pure ice in his veins.
不管什么情况都脸不改色心不跳
We were pinned down once, like, two bullets left.
有一次我们寡不敌众,就剩两颗子弹了
I looked over. Not one bead of sweat.
我看他,连汗都不带出的
Was cool.
真是太酷了
Yeah. Can I help you up there?
帅,要我帮你吗
You're a mechanic now?
你还是机修工
Of course I am a mechanic. I am whatever you need me to be, sir.
我当然是机修工,你要我是什么,我就是什么
Okay, then just be quiet.
好吧,我要你闭嘴
Uh, yes, sir.
嗯,是,长官
Tiger.
老虎
This sniper I knew, I mean, this guy got it all figured out.
我认识的一个狙击手,把狙击研究得透透的
Wind speed, temperature.
什么风速啊,温度啊
Shit, barometric pressure.
还有什么气压之类的
But do you know what he said was the most important?
你知道他说什么才是最重要的吗
- No.   - Patience.
- 不知道  - 耐心
- Really?   - Yeah, he said that.
- 真的  - 真的,他这么说的
This thing smells good. What is that? Is it kerosene? Gasoline?
这玩意儿是什么,真好闻,煤油吗,汽油吗
What is that?
是什么
- Aviation fuel.   - Aviation fuel.
- 航空燃油  - 原来是航空燃油
It's good.
真好闻
The best team member ever.
有史以来最棒的队员
His name was Torres. Holy shit.
他的名字叫托雷斯,我的天呐
You wouldn't believe what this guy was capable to do.
那家伙什么都会,无所不能
Unbelievable. I'm telling you.
简直不可思议,我跟你说
- Galgo.   - Yes, sir.
- 高格  - 是,长官
I think I know why your team let you go.
我知道你的团队为什么不要你
You do? Really?
是吗,真的
Yes!
真棒
Big plane.
好大的飞机
Old, old, but cool, ya know.
虽然够老,但酷得很
- Where are the others?   - Just us.
- 其他人在哪里?  - 只有我们
- Just us?   - Just us.
- 就我们?  - 就我们
Insane.
疯了
Courageous, but insane.
勇气可嘉,但还是疯了
Last chance.
最后问你一次
You sure you wanna do this?
你真的要跟我去吗
I like traveling.
我喜欢旅行
Good.
很好
Uh... Who are those guys?
这些人是谁啊
My old team.
我的老队员
What the hell are you doing here?
你们来这儿干什么
You were stupid enough to get yourself into this mess!
只有你这种笨蛋会蠢到会趟这浑水
We're the only ones crazy enough to get you out of it!
也只有我们会疯到去把你拉出来
Come on. We're late for a war!
快上来,打仗要迟到了
Galgo, you might wanna get outta that seat. Christmas is comin'.
高格,你还是别坐这个位子了,圣诞到了
But it's June.
可现在才六月份
Galgo, get the hell out!
高格,快给我出去
Yes, sir. My hat and gloves.
是,长官,我拿一下,我的帽子
- I'm curious.   - What?
- 我很好奇  - 什么
Since when did suicide become your hobby?
你什么时候开始把自杀当爱好了
I got a will.
我立了份遗嘱
You know, I'm probably the only friend you've got.
我大概是你现在唯一的朋友了
I've got lots of friends.
我朋友多着呢
You walk into a room, people jump under tables.
是啊,只要你一出现,大家都欢呼雀跃
I missed you, Christmas.
我真想你,圣诞
I missed you, too, you demented bastard.
我也想你,你这个疯狂的混蛋
You could've left the "demented" out.
你可以把疯狂两个字去掉
It's a kind of a solid structure that is taking us from one place to another
这样一种坚固的固体结构,在以难以置信的速度
to unbelievable speeds.
把我们从一个地方带到另一个地方
Think about it! If God...
好好想想
If God, if he would have liked us,
如果,如果,如果上帝
you know, flying, he would have given us feathers.
希望我们飞翔,他会让我们身上长翅膀
Do you have feathers?
你有翅膀吗
Do you have feathers? Do you have feathers?
你有翅膀吗,你有翅膀吗
I don't have feathers.
我没有翅膀
Damn. This is gonna be a long-ass flight, fellas.
这次飞行会很漫长
It's going to be. It's going to be a long flight.
肯定会是一次,会是一次漫长的飞行
But don't worry. I'm here. Man, because I can't sleep on planes.
别担心,有我呢,我在飞机上,一向睡不着
Yeah.
喂
I thought you should know, Barney,
我希望你知道,巴尼
you're walking into a shitstorm.
你在往屎坑里跳
NSA ran a signals and frequency check on your team's phones.
国家安全局搜索了你那些被抓队员的手机信号
This bastard's not even trying to hide 'em.
那混蛋都没想把他们藏起来
- Where's he taken 'em?   - They're in Azmenistan.
- 他们在哪儿  - 他们在阿兹门尼斯坦
Another honeymoon hotspot.
又是个度蜜月的好地方
Who is that?
谁在说话
Lee Christmas.
李·圣诞
Not far off, Christmas.
离圣诞是不远了
Stonebanks' compound is where he trains his goons.
斯通班克斯在那儿训练手下的雇佣兵
It's very heavily fortified.
那里的防守非常严密
What's up with the local army?
当地的军队怎么回事
I don't understand a word this guy is sayin'.
这家伙说的话我一句也没听懂
Local army status.
他问当地军队的情况
Small. Corrupt.
小军队,很腐败
Stonebanks' has got all the brass in his pocket.
斯通班克斯的口袋里有的是钱
Been running his operations through
他已经在那个该死的地方
this shithole of a country for years.
随心所欲好几年了
- Want some advice?   - What's the advice?
- 想听建议吗  - 你的建议是什么
What goddamn language is that?
那家伙说的是什么鸟语
You know, to tell you the truth, I don't understand you either.
我也听不懂你想说什么
Look who's talkin'.
还有脸说我
What's the advice, Drummer?
你有什么建议
Forget about what you're thinking.
忘掉个人恩怨吧
Remember our deal. We need him alive.
记住我们的约定,我们要抓活的
So he can sit in a courtroom
好让他在法庭上
and beat this on a technicality?
钻法律的空子解脱罪行
Those are orders, Barney.
这可是命令,巴尼
- You broke the phone.   - I got another one.
- 对讲机砸坏了  - 还有一个呢
Think we'll make it back from this one?
这次我们能活着回去吗
You didn't have to come along, Christmas.
你没必要跟我一起去
Sure, I did.
当然有必要
Morons need friends.
笨蛋需要有人罩着
Gentlemen, change of plans.
先生们,计划改变了
This is it? This is your evac team?
就你们俩,这就是你的救援队
Short notice.
时间仓促嘛
Yeah, very short.
是啊,长得也够仓促
Where's your team, Major Drummer?
你的团队呢,鼓手少校
No team. This one's off the books.
没有团队,这次是私人行动
I'm not even here.
我根本没来过这儿
Nobody's here.
是啊,没有人来过这儿
I thought Church was asshole.
我本来以为,就教堂是流氓
The only army in the world.
世界上仅剩的军队
Whoa. Guys, did I tell you about Pepito?
伙计们,我提到过佩皮托吗?
Small name, big guy.
人小志气大
I saw him lift a deuce and a half of a guy once.
我看到过他手撕壮汉对半开
I love that tattoo, man.
我爱那个刺青
I like that kind of, black chicken that you have there. What is that called?
我喜欢这种类型,你那上面刻的黑鸡叫什么名字?
A craw. The craw over the skull. I love to do something...
乌鸦,配骷髅头的乌鸦,我喜欢这么干...
Yeah. Hysterical strength. Weird.
对,他们把这叫做精神力量,多奇怪
Yes, sir. Weird concept.
是,长官,奇怪的概念
I mean, if you are hysterically strong, you don't even have to go to the gym.
如果一个人他有很强的精神力量,都不用去健身房锻炼了
You are just strong. You just got it. You just got it.
你天生就强,你就是强,你就是强
But hysterical is a concept that actually
不过这个词在19世纪,其实
was applied to women in the 19th century.
其实是被用来表示女人的歇斯底里症
It's a decimononic concept. You know what I mean?
当时这是一个病理概念,知道什么意思吗
Wow. This is an interesting place.
喔,这地方真有意思
- He gave me a migraine.   - I hear that.
- 他让我偏头痛  - 可不是嘛
Don't you think? A bit cold, too.
你觉得怎么样?,冷得要死
Look on the bright side.
往好了看
You run out of bullets, he can talk 'em to death.
万一没弹药了,他能把敌人说死
Roger that.
好主意
Tall one doesn't like me.
高个子不喜欢我
- He doesn't like anybody.   - Yeah.
- 他不喜欢任何人  - 是的
- What'd you say?   - He likes you.
- 你说什么  - 他喜欢你
What the hell is that?
那是什么玩意儿
- What?   - That computer strapped to your wrist?
- 什么  - 你手上绑的是电脑
Nothin'.
没什么
It's the same thing you were busting that kid's balls about?
是你上回嘲笑那孩子用的玩意儿
No, I had it for a while now.
不,我用了一阵儿了
Why'd your team let you go?
你的团队为什么不要你
Why does it matter now?
问这个干嘛
I wanna know who I'm working with.
我想了解我的同事
Well, they aren't around anymore.
他们,他们都已经不在了
So, listen, um...
那么,当初
So Why'd they let you go?
怎么会扔下你
They didn't.
没有扔下我
Benghazi.
在班加西
I was not in the army anymore and we were
那时候我已经退役了,我们
retrieving a hostage, something like...
去解救一个人质,有点儿像
Like we are doing here, and, uh...
我们现在做的事
It was... A beautiful day.
然后,那天天气很好
No problems.
一切顺利
And then it all went bad.
然后情况突然变糟了
We got hit. Cut off.
我们遭到了袭击,没退路了
Waited for support. No one came.
等待支援,没有人来
And...
后来
Everybody died.
所有人都死了
Except me.
只剩下了我
Mingo,
明格,
Torres, and Tiger, right?
托雷斯,还有老虎
You were listening.
你听着呢
Yeah, I was listening.
是的,我听着呢
Thank you.
谢谢
So what do you think?
你怎么想
I think we should get this over with.
我们过去做个了断吧
Four signals.
四个人
Eight stories up.
在第八层
This is way too wrong. Sally don't like it.
这很不正常,我感觉不对劲
You know he's got eyes on us now.
他肯定在盯着我们
May I suggest something?
我能提一个小建议吗
No. No, later.
不行,现在不行
That's what I thought. It's fine.
就知道会这样,好吧
Go!
上
Break it.
弄开它
Oh, shit.
见鬼
What the hell?
噢,搞什么
Hey, Barn!
嗨,巴尼
I knew you couldn't stay away.
我知道你一定会来的
But I'm relieved that someone could pick up the kids.
不过有人能来接这些孩子也好
You got 'em in there?
你找到他们了
Now try getting 'em out.
想办法带他们出去吧
But unfortunately for you,
可不幸的是
the entire complex has been wired with C-4.
整栋大楼都装上了C4炸药
It'd take a regular Joe about 90 seconds to get out of there.
一般人用90秒就能从里面出来
You've got... How 'bout 45?
至于你嘛,45秒够吗
(引爆倒计时)
He's turned this whole place into a bomb.
他把这儿变成了个大炸弹
Maybe not.
我来试试
9% battery power. You didn't charge it?
只剩9%,你没充电吗
Excuse me, but what are you doing?
不好意思,你在干什么
Just running some code. Should be able to jam the signal.
运行某些代码,应该能干扰信号
Why didn't you think of that?
你怎么没想到
Well, I use it to check the weather.
我只用它看天气
Will you just shut up and let him do his thing?
你们能不能闭嘴,别干扰他
You sure you can do this, Thorn?
你能行吗,索恩
I can do it. I can do it.
我能行,我能行
Yeah, kid, take your time.
别着急,别着急
Come on, man. Come on, come on.
快啊,伙计,加油,加油
Come on, dude.
加油,伙计
- Come on. Come on!   - Come on!
- 快点儿  - 快点儿
Come on. Come on, Thorn. Come on, Thorn.
加油,快点儿,索恩,快点儿,索恩
Give me a sec.
别着急
- Source is in.   - You can do it. Come on, Thorn.
- 打开开关  - 你能行的,加油,索恩
Come on, come on.
快点儿,快点儿
Focus. Focus.
安静,安静
Got it!
搞定
I take it back.
干得好,太棒了,太棒了
We've lost override. The signal is jammed.
不能重写了,信号被干扰了
Send 'em in.
叫他们来
Barney, the battery's at 8%. When this thing dies, we lose override.
电量还剩8%,一旦没电就无法干扰了
That gives us about 25 minutes, tops.
这样我们最多有25分钟
Don't pop the bottles yet. Still got trouble.
还有麻烦呢
- What?   - Big trouble.
- 什么 - 而且是大麻烦
Lucky again, bro.
运气不错
But try to enjoy the view because
趁现在好好欣赏风景吧
shortly, the building that you're currently standing in
很快你们所在的这栋大楼,它就会
will be surrounded by the Azmenistan army.
就会被阿兹门尼斯坦的军队包围了
Oh, shit.
见鬼
How did you shitheads manage to get captured anyway?
都是你们这群白痴惹的祸
Shut up!
闭嘴
Step back!
都退后
It's not an accident
这不是意外
that we're trapped in here!
我们被困在这儿
This is exactly what he knew would happen.
他很清楚,会发生这种事
Us tearing at each other.
他想,让我们自相残杀
It stops now!
你们不能这样
We can do this.
我们能逃出去
But only if we do this
可我们必须要
together.
齐心协力
If we work as a team,
如果我们相互配合
we just may get out of this alive.
我们就有希望活着离开这里
Now, do you wanna make it work?
你们想活着离开吗
That simple.
很简单
You got any weapons?
你有武器吗
Here's the plan. We're gonna break up into small groups
计划是这样
and go out through the ground floor.
我们分成几个小组,从底楼冲出去
Get ready!
准备好
Come on.
走吧
- Thorn, you stay with me. You take Galgo.   - I don't want to.
- 索恩,你跟我一组,你带高格  - 我才不要呢
Don't stop. One there. One there.
别停下,一个去那儿,一个去那儿
There's too many!
他们人太多了
They're on our flank! Bring it to 'em!
他们在侧面,快去干掉他们
Bring it!
干掉他们
Enough's enough. Light 'em up.
够了,炸死他们
Incoming!
炮弹来了
Up the shaft, Thorn. You gotta protect that signal jammer.
索恩,你去电梯井,保护好信号干扰器
I thought you could fight!
侧面掩护,快
Jesus! You okay?
天呐,你没事吧
You Okay?
我没事
Totally fine! Totally fine!
可爽了
And full of energy. You know, we are brothers now!
浑身是劲,我们现在是兄弟了!
Good, keep moving!
很好,继续前进
Yes, sir!
是,长官!
Relax.
放松点儿
I told you you'd give yourself a stroke.
我说了,你老这样容易中风
Drummer?
鼓手
You got a tank problem, pal.
伙计,有坦克找你麻烦
Do something about it.
你想想办法
I'm on it.
我正想呢
Trench, on your right!
战壕,注意右边
That's gotta hurt.
一定很疼
Drummer's in the house!
我请客,吃炮弹
Hey. Look!
嗨,快看
Let's go!
我们走
Time to pick up the tempo, boys.
孩子们,该加快速度了
Not good. Hold on.
小心后面直升机
This is not happening.
情况不妙
You wanna do something?
抓紧
Pull me down! Pull me...
怎么会这样,干你的活儿去
Oh, shit.
噢,见鬼
Hi, there.
嗨,你好
Closer.
近点儿
再近点儿
Yang, hit something.
阴阳,快给我打
Excellent.
谢谢
Your name is Luna, right? Luna means "moon."
你叫卢娜,对吗,卢娜的意思是月亮
Hypnotic, mysterious, magical, like yourself.
充满梦幻,充满神秘,又神奇,就像你
Would you like to hold my gun?
你能拿着我的家伙吗
Come on, drive this thing!
我去拿你的家伙
My mom drove a tank back in Sweden.
来吧,开起来
This one's for Caesar, assholes!
这是为了凯撒,混蛋们
- Yeah!   - Damn, that's cool!
- 耶  - 喔,太爽了
I had it all under control.
都在我掌握之中
Yeah, that's what it looked like.
看上去是这样的
Come on!
拜托
This is the happiest moment of my life!
这是我这辈子最开心的时刻
Jing-a-ling, jing-a-ling.
叮叮当,叮叮当
You finished yet?
搞定了吗
Men.
臭男人
- You're not gonna believe this.   - Oh, God.
- 你一定不会相信的  - 噢,天呐
I've been thinking about you the whole time.
我脑子里一直都在想着你
- During the whole fight.   - Can we just go?
- 你真能打  - 能走了吗
Come on.
拜托
Hold on!
抓紧
Where did you learn how to fly?
你在哪儿学的开飞机
Trench, you're on.
该你上了,战壕
Barney! We got reinforcements!
巴尼,增援部队来了
Shit!
见鬼
Drummer, there's another wave coming.
鼓手,他们又来了一拨
The only way out is up.
只能从上面出去了
On my way. Evac in five.
我马上到,5秒钟后撤离
Got it!
收到
Everybody get to the roof now!
所有人上屋顶,快
Got it.
收到
Trench. Yang. Come on, clear the roof!
战壕,阴阳,快去清理屋顶
Let's go!
我们走
Always this easy? Pretty much.
该死
How hard can it be to kill 10 men?
每次都这么容易,差不多
You think you could even just wound a couple?
杀十个人有那么难吗,至少打伤几个吧
Watch closely.
给我瞧着
And again.
再来一次
Anybody else?
都会了吗
Useless bunch of...
没用的废物
If you want something done right...
还得我亲自出马
They got valet parking here?
这里有人代客泊车吗
Yeah, there's some right here.
嗨,那边有几个
Go, go, go!
走,走,走
Don't stop!
别停下
Come on, guys, move it!
快,伙计们,快走
Drummer, we're pinned down!
鼓手,火力太猛
Stop mumbling.
别叽里咕噜的
Good morning!
早上好
Let's get to the chopper!
我们上直升机吧
Let's go!
快走
Go, go, go, go, go! Come on, move, go, go!
走,走,走,走,走,快点儿,快走
Gotta go, gotta go.
快,我们得走了
- Yang?   - You're welcome.
- 阴阳  - 不用谢
You're working for Trench?
你在为战壕工作
Yeah. He pay me more money.
是啊,他开的工资高
Who the hell are you?
你他妈是谁
I'm the guy that just saved your ass.
刚刚救了你命的人
Battery's at 2%.
电量还剩2%
Hey, Barney, leaving so soon?
嗨,巴尼,这么快就走吗
Come on, let's finish this.
咱们做个了断吧
How ya feelin'?
感觉怎么样
Come on, stand up. You'll feel better.
站起来,会感觉好点儿
Barney, where are you?
巴尼,你在哪儿
Lose the armor. I want you to feel this.
把防弹衣脱了,我让你好好感受感受
Barney, we gotta go!
巴尼,我们得撤了
And don't even think about going for that piece of garbage in the back.
别再想着去拿你藏在背后的那块废铁了
Come on.
扔了
That's it.
这就对了
No, we don't need these, do we?
我也用不着这个了
Come on.
来啊
Barney, we've gotta go!
巴尼,我们得快走
Battery's at 1%!
电量只剩1%了
Come on, Barney!
快点儿,巴尼
Motherfucker.
妈的
What about The Hague, huh?
不是要送我去海牙吗
I am The Hague.
我就是海牙
Battery's gone!
没电了
Gotta go! Gotta go!
我们走,我们走
No! No, wait! Wait!
不,等等,再等等
Can't wait!
不能等了
CHRISTMAS; Go!
快
Come on, Barney! Go!
快点儿,巴尼,快跑
What the hell?
来不及了
You owe me, Barney.
永别了,巴尼
Barney! Barney!
巴尼,巴尼
Holy...
见鬼
Pull me up!
拉我上去
You gonna fire us again, Barney?
你敢再解雇我们吗
Come on!
拜托
Can't hear you, pal.
我听不见
I'm gonna kill you.
我要宰了你
All right, I'm sorry! Pull me up, you idiots!
行了,对不起,拉我上去,你们这帮笨蛋
Don't pull him up.
别让他上来
To Caesar!
敬凯撒,凯撒
Caesar!
凯撒,凯撒,凯撒
Yeah!
凯撒
- Hey, yo, Barney.   - Yeah.
- 耶,嗨,巴尼  - 什么
I don't think I'm gonna be needing this anymore.
我想我不需要这个了
You want your luck back?
把好运收回去吧
I hope I didn't stretch it.
但愿没被我撑大
I think you did stretch it.
你已经撑大了
Good to have you back, man.
很高兴你回来
Don't scare us like that anymore, okay?
不许再这么吓唬我们了
- Hale Caesar.   - To me!
- 强壮凯撒  - 敬我自己
You never got him to The Hague.
你没把他送到海牙
You know, Drummer, working with you ain't been so bad.
我说,鼓手,跟你合作也不算糟糕
I haven't had so much fun in years.
我好久没玩得这么开心了
Fun's important.
开心最重要
These guys are nuts.
这些家伙都是神经病
Our powers combined...
我这个帅吧
Is that a Captain Planet reference?
那是"地球超人"装逼指南吗?
- I'm fire.   - Yeah, you are.
- 我很惹火  - 没错
Come on, if you had to be a Planeteer...
得了,如果你非要做救星者的话...
Are you calling Captain Planet?
你外号"地球超人"是吗?
Whoa. Major old-school.
噢,老派少校
Hey, Major Badass.
嗨,坏蛋少校
I'll drink to that.
你这小子
I am sure
我相信
I have done enough that I am worth my weight in gold, you know.
我表现得这么好,说明我这个人真的很有价值
Am I close? And since I am as crazy as you,
我有希望吗,既然我跟你一样疯狂
uh, l am sure I'll fit in.
我相信我适合这个团队
- Galgo.   - Yes, sir.
- 高格  - 是,长官
Welcome aboard.
欢迎加入敢死队
Thank God!
感谢上帝
Because I already spent a fortune on this. You know what I mean?
我纹这个花了好大一笔钱,你懂我意思吗
I am so happy!
我真是太高兴了
Barney, thank you. Yeah.
巴尼,谢谢
No, no, no, no, no. No, no hugging, no.
不不不,不要拥抱,不要
No hugging. No hugging
不要,不要
No hugging. No, no, no, no, no.
不要拥抱
Best two out of three.
三局两胜
Just wanted to say thanks.
我只想谢谢你
- For what?   - For caring.
- 谢什么  - 谢谢你的关心
Oh, come on.
得了
Yeah. Thanks.
噢,谢谢
You know, if you were 30 years younger...
如果你年轻30岁
I'd be afraid of you.
我肯定会怕你的
Here, cheers.
干杯
Hey, Yang. Looks like you had a growth spurt.
嗨,阴阳,你好像长高点儿了嘛
Tall people don't live long.
个子高的人活不长
So you're working for Trench now.
你现在为战壕工作了
And you, I thought you retired.
还有你,你不是退休了吗
- I lied.   - Good.
- 我骗你的  - 行啊
You guys wanna get a room?
你们去开房间吧
We don't need any rooms.
我们哪儿需要开房
So jealous.
你真会吃醋
We came into this thing together, we gonna leave here together.
我们是大家一起来的,走也要一起走
- Hear me?   - Absolutely.
- 听见吗  - 当然
- Cheers.   - Cheers.
- 干杯  - 干杯
You know, for a guy that doesn't take orders very well,
对一个不愿意听命令的人来说
you did pretty good.
你表现得不错
Yeah?
是吗
So when do I take over?
那我几时能接班
Keep drinkin'.
喝你的酒吧
Hey, Smilee!
嗨,斯麦利
Get over here.
到这儿来
You did good, kid.
你干得很好
∮ Old man, look at my life ∮
∮ 老人家,看看我的生活 ∮
∮ Twenty-four and there's so much more ∮
∮ 24岁,我的时间还有很多 ∮
∮ Live alone in a paradise ∮
∮ 独自在天堂生活 ∮
∮ That makes me think of two ∮
∮ 想找个伴儿一起过 ∮
∮ Love lost, such a cost... ∮
∮ 爱情的代价太大 ∮
You look like a proud, demented father.
∮ 你就像个自豪的疯狂的老爸 ∮
You coulda skipped the "demented" part.
你可以去掉疯狂这两个字
It was a compliment.
我是在夸你呢
《敢死队3》